Guide to the Cleanth Brooks Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1933-86; Series I; 6.5; (16 boxes)
  - Lewis, R. W. B., 1949-51 (Box 6, Folder 165)
  - Lewis, Wilmarth S., 1958-68 (Box 6, Folder 166)
  - Lewis, Wyndham, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 167)
  - Leyburn, James G., 1963-68 (Box 7, Folder 168)
  - Library of Congress, 1948-64, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 169-72)
    See also: Box 90, folder 1938
  - Lincoln, Robert A., 1966-86, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 173)
  - Lowell, Robert ("Cal"), 1954-67, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 174)
  - Lowell, Robert (Mrs.)
    See: Jean Stafford
  - Lytle, Andrew Nelson, 1940-85, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 175)
  - "M" general, 1935-86, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 176-79)
  - Macauley, Robie
    See: The Kenyon Review
  - Mack, Maynard, 1942-84 (Box 7, Folder 180)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1955 Feb 28 (Box 7, Folder 181)
  - McLuhan, Marshall, 1945-49 (Box 7, Folder 182-83)
  - McLuhan, Marshall, 1950-77, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 184-85)
  - Mann, C. S., 1966-69, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 186)
  - Martz, Louis L. and Edwine Montague ("Eddie"), 1959-85, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 187)
  - Masefield, John, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 188)
  - Mason, Francis, 1967-68, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 189)
  - Massey, Linton, 1960-68 (Box 8, Folder 190)
  - Matthiesen, F. O., 1942-43, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 191)
  - Merchant, Moelwyn, 1957-85, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 192-94)
  - Meredith, William, 1957-78 (Box 8, Folder 195)
  - Meriwether, James B., 1964-84, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 196-204)
  - Mizener, Arthur, 1940-71, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 205)
  - Monk, Samuel H., 1941-59 (Box 9, Folder 206)
  - Montesi, Albert J., 1954-67 (Box 9, Folder 207)
  - Moore, Marianne, 1952-53 (Box 9, Folder 208)
  - "N" general, 1955-86, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 209)
  - "O" general, 1950-85, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 210)
  - O'Connor, Flannery, 1959 Apr 12 (Box 9, Folder 211)
  - O'Connor, William Van, 1946-62, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 212)
  - Olney, James, 1981-85, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 213)
  - Osborn, James Marshall, also contains "Tribute" by Cleanth Brooks, 1964-78, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 214)
  - Owsley, Harriet, 1983-86 (Box 9, Folder 215)
  - "P" general, 1935-86, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 216-18)
  - Palmer, John J. E., 1940-85, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 219-21)
  - Percy, LeRoy and Ami, 1983-85, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 222)
  - Percy, Walker, 1970-86, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 223)
  - Polk, Noel, 1974-85, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 224)
  - Porter, Katherine Anne, 1940-85, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 225-30)
    See also: Isabel Bayley
  - Porter, M. Gilbert, 1981-82 (Box 10, Folder 231)
  - Potter, Stanley, 1934-61, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 232)
  - Pound, Ezra
    See: The Bollingen Prize in Poetry, Box 87, folder 1783
  - Price, Reynolds, 1964-72 (Box 10, Folder 233)
  - Purdy, James, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 234)
  - "Q" general, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 235)
  - "R" general, 1936-86, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 236-37)
  - Rajan, B., 1944-58, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 238)
  - Ransom, Harry, 1953-60, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 239)
  - Ransom, John Crowe, 1934-63 (Box 10, Folder 240-41)
  - Ransom, John Crowe, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 242-43)
  - Read, W. A., 1938-62 (Box 11, Folder 244)
  - Richards, I. A., 1940-73, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 245)
  - Riding, Laura
    See: Laura Riding Jackson
  - Rubin, Louis D., Jr., 1951-86, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 246-47)
  - Russell, Peter, 1949-75, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 248)
  - "S" general, 1941-86, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 249-53)
  - St. John-Stevas, Norman, 1957-85, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 254)
  - Schwartz, Delmore, 1960, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 255)
  - Sensibar, Judith L., 1983-84, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 256)
  - Shapiro, Karl, 1948-50, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 257)
  - Simpson, Lewis P., 1963-86, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 258-59)
  - Singers-Bigger, Gladys, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 260)
  - Smith, Jeffery, 1934-64, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 261)
  - Spears, Monroe K., 1952-84, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 262)
  - Spender, Stephen, 1953-73, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 263)
  - Spitzer, Leo, 1952-54 (Box 12, Folder 264)
  - Stafford, Jean (Mrs. Robert Lowell), ca. 1940s, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 265)
  - Stallman, Robert W., 1944-52, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 266)
  - Stanford, Donald E., 1963-81, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 267)
  - "T" general, 1933-86, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 268-70)
  - Tassin, Anthony, 1965-85 (Box 12, Folder 271)
  - Tate, Allen, 1933-49 (Box 12, Folder 272-75)
  - Tate, Allen, 1950-79, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 276-79)
  - Taylor, Peter, 1946-69, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 280)
  - Toledano, Ben C. and Roulhac, 1963-83, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 281)
  - Trilling, Lionel, 1942-67, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 282)
  - "U" general, 1941-85 (Box 13, Folder 283)
  - Unger, Leonard, 1941-83 (Box 13, Folder 284)
  - "V" general, 1948-84 (Box 13, Folder 285)
  - Van Doren, Mark, 1948 May 3 (Box 13, Folder 286)
  - Vivas, Eliseo, 1955-60, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 287)
  - Voegelin, Eric, 1944-74, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 288)
  - "W" general, 1935-91, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 289-91)
  - Wade, John D., 1943-47 (Box 13, Folder 292)
  - Wallace, John M., 1982 (Box 13, Folder 293)
  - Walsh, John, 1977-85, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 294)
  - Warren, Austin, 1943-76 (Box 13, Folder 295)
  - Warren, Eleanor Clark, 1952-84, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 296-299)
  - Warren, Emma Brescia ("Cinina"), 1941-48 (Box 14, Folder 300)
  - Warren, Gabriel, 1969, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 301)
  - Warren, Robert Penn ("Red"), 1933-74 (Box 14, Folder 302-10)
  - Warren, Robert Penn ("Red"), 1975-86, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 311-15)
  - Warren, Rosanna Phelps ("Roposie"), 1958-86 (Box 15, Folder 316-18)
  - Warwick, Gould, 1983-86 (Box 15, Folder 319)
  - Weaver, Richard M., 1944-71, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 320)
  - Weiss, Klaus, 1966-83 (Box 15, Folder 321)
  - Wellek, René, 1953-85, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 322)
  - Welty, Eudora, 1941-80, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 323)
  - West, Rebecca, 1963-68 (Box 15, Folder 324)
  - Wheelwright, Philip, 1954-61 (Box 15, Folder 325)
  - White, Jon Manchip, 1967-82, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 326)
  - Wilder, Thornton and Isabel, 1949-73, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 327-28)
  - Wildman, John, 1960-61, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 329)
  - Williams, Aubrey, 1956-85, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 330)
  - Wimsatt, William K. and Margaret, 1943-85, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 331-333)
  - Wolfenden, John, Sir, 1966-71 (Box 16, Folder 334)
  - Woodhouse, A. S. P., 1950-52 (Box 16, Folder 335)
  - Woodward, C. Vann, 1969-85, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 336)
  - Wordsworth, Jonathan, 1966-70 (Box 16, Folder 337)
  - Wright, Stuart, 1983-85, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 338)
  - "Y" general, 1967-85 (Box 16, Folder 339)
  - Yeats, William Butler, 1937-60 (Box 16, Folder 340)
  - Young, Stark, 1935-39, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 341)
  - "Z" general, 1980-84 (Box 16, Folder 342)
  - Zabel, Morton Dauwen, 1940-63, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 343)
  - Unidentified, 1943-86, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 344-45)
- Writings, 1928-86; Series II; 26.5; (64 boxes)
  Series II, Writings (Boxes 17-80), is divided into four subseries, Bibliography, Percy Editorial Project, Books, and Shorter Works.
  - BIBLIOGRAPHY
    - Bibliography, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 346)
  - PERCY EDITORIAL PROJECT
    Research material in the Percy Editorial Project subseries is arranged alphabetically by correspondent and institution. The remaining material is arranged alphabetically by folder title under appropriate subject headings.
    - Correspondence
      - Percy-Anderson: copies, 1985-86, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 347)
      - Percy-Apperley: copies, 1953-62, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 348)
      - Percy-Astle: copies, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 349)
      - Percy-Boswell: copies, 1968-73, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 350)
      - Percy-Bowle
        - Copies, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 351-52)
        - Research notes, 1962-65, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 353)
        - List of correspondence, 1986, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 354)
        - "Ride to Hulne Abbey" [1765 Aug 5], n.d. (Box 17, Folder 355)
      - Percy-Cleiveland: abstracts (Box 17, Folder 356)
      - Percy-Farmer: copies, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 357-60)
      - Percy-Grainger: copies, 1946-78, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 361)
      - Percy-Malone: copies, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 362)
      - Percy-Paton
        - Copies, 1956-60, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 363)
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 364)
      - Percy-Pinkerton
        - Copies, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 365)
          See also: Box 94, folder 1986
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 366)
        - Correspondence, 1982-84, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 367)
      - Percy-Shenstone
        - Copies in the Osborn Collection, Beinecke Library, Yale University, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 368)
        - Copies not on microfilm, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 369)
        - Research material, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 370-73)
        - Research material re Cutler MS at Wellesley College, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 374)
        - Research material, Shenstone's Pastoral Ballad, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 375)
        - Research notes, 1947-69, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 376-77)
        - Research notes & correspondence, 1975, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 378-79)
        - Research notes, Problems with, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 380)
        - Things to do, 1967 Jul (Box 19, Folder 381)
      - Percy-Warburton: copies
        See: Box 94, folder 1987
    - Correspondence at Institutions
      - Bodleian Library, Oxford University
        - Copies, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 382-83)
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 384-85)
      - Ecton Collection: copies, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 386)
      - Houghton Library, Harvard University
        - Copies, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 387)
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 388)
      - Huntington Library: research notes, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 389)
      - Osborn Collection, Beinecke Library, Yale University: copies, 1977-78, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 390)
    - Miscellaneous
      - General: copies, 1943, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 391)
      - General: research material, 1954, 1962, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 392-97)
      - Percy letters re new edition of the Chinese novels, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 398)
      - A chronological list of the unpublished correspondence of Thomas Percy (Box 20, Folder 399)
      - General: research notes, 1947-77, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 400)
      - Research notes for lost letters, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 401)
    - Journal
      - Statistical record of entries, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 402)
      - Copies, typescript
        - Early (1746-79 with gaps), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 403-04)
        - Early (1780-1811 with gaps), n.d. (Box 21, Folder 405-06)
        - Later (1746-64 with gaps), n.d. (Box 21, Folder 407-08)
    - Subject Files
      - Blakeway family genealogical records, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 409)
      - Bridgnorth, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 410)
      - Dodsley's fables: research notes, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 411)
      - Easton Mauduit, 1951-69 (Box 21, Folder 412)
      - Maidlow account book, 1755-1794, 1755-94 (Box 21, Folder 413)
      - Percy and the Hyndford MS (Box 21, Folder 414)
      - Percy family genealogical records, 1952-78 (Box 21, Folder 415)
        See also: Box 94, folders 1988-89
      - Percy material owned by Cleanth Brooks donated to the Osborn Collection, List of (Box 21, Folder 416)
      - Percy, Material peripheral to, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 417)
      - Percy's library: list of holdings, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 418)
      - Reliques of Ancient English Poetry: chronology from beginning through publication as revealed in Percy's correspondence (Box 22, Folder 419)
      - Shenstone family genealogical records, 1961, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 420)
    - Printed Works: Articles on Percy
      - Bowle, John, "A Letter to the Reverend Dr. Percy concerning a New and Classical Edition of Historica del Valeroso Cavallero Don Quixote de la Mancha [1777]": printed version, photocopy (Box 22, Folder 421)
      - Brooks, Cleanth, "The History of Percy's Edition of Surrey's Poems": offprint, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 422)
      - Brooks, Cleanth, "Thomas Percy, Don Quixote, and Don Bowle": offprint, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 423)
      - Clark, Robert T., Jr., "Herder, Percy, and the Song of Songs ": offprint, 1946 Dec (Box 22, Folder 424)
      - Dennis, Leah
        - "'Blandamour' in the Percy-Ritson Controversy": offprint, 1931 Nov (Box 22, Folder 425)
        - "'Gill Morice' in the Reliques again": offprint, 1941 Apr (Box 22, Folder 426)
        - "Percy's Essay 'On the Ancient Metrical Romances'": offprint, 1934 Mar (Box 22, Folder 427)
        - "The Text of the Percy-Watson Letters": offprint, 1931 Dec (Box 22, Folder 428)
        - "Thomas Percy: Antiquarian vs. Man of Taste": offprint, 1942 Mar (Box 22, Folder 429)
      - Falconer, A. F., "Bishop Percy's Annotated Copy of Lord Hailes Ancient Scottish Poems'": offprint, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 430)
      - Friedman, Albert B.
        - "The First Draft of Percy's Reliques ": offprint, 1954 Dec (Box 22, Folder 431)
        - "Percy's Folio Manuscript Revalued": offprint, 1954 Oct (Box 22, Folder 432)
      - Powell, L. F., "Percy's Reliques ": offprint, 1928 Sep (Box 22, Folder 433)
      - Wagener, Haucke Friedrich, Das Eindringen von Percy's Reliques in Deutschland [1897], trans. by Charles B. Teske: typescript, 1962-63 (Box 22, Folder 434)
      - Watkins-Jones, A., "Bishop Percy, Thomas Warton, and Chatterton's Rowley Poems (1773-1790)": offprint, 1935 Sep (Box 22, Folder 435)
    - Printed Works: Articles on Contemporaries
      - Baker, Stewart A., "Sannazaro and Milton's Brief Epic": offprint, 1968 Jul (Box 22, Folder 436)
      - O'Flaherty, Patrick, "John Pinkerton (1758-1826): Champion of the Makars": offprint, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 437)
      - Riely, John, "Shenstone's Walks: The Genesis of The Leasowes": offprint, 1979 Sep (Box 22, Folder 438)
      - S., F. H., "Dr. Johnson in Cambridge": offprint, 1965-66 (Box 22, Folder 439)
      - Warnock, Robert, "Nuove Lettere inedite di Guiseppe Baretti" [re Baretti- Boswell correspondence]: offprint, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 440)
    - Published Works
      - An Edition of the Correspondence between Thomas Percy and Richard Farmer [British Museum Add. MS. 28,222]: A Thesis for the Degree of Bachelor of Letters by Cleanth Brooks, Exeter College [Oxford University ]: typescript carbon, corrected, 1932 (Box 22, Folder 441)
      - The Correspondence of Thomas Percy and Richard Farmer
        - Brooks, Cleanth, "Introduction": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 442)
      - The Correspondence of Thomas Percy and William Shenstone
        - "Introduction": holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 443)
        - "Introduction": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 444)
        - "Introduction": typescript, photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 445)
        - Table of letters: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 446)
        - Transcription of letters: typescript, corrected, parts I-IV, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 447-50)
        - Manuscript: typescript, photocopy, corrected, with printer's annotations, parts I-II, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 451-52)
        - Appendix I: holograph (Box 23, Folder 453)
        - Appendix I: typescript, corrected ("Shenstone's Billets") (Box 23, Folder 454)
        - Appendix I: typescript, photocopy, with printer's annotations ("Shenstone's Billets") (Box 24, Folder 455)
        - Appendix I: blues ("Shenstone's Billets") (Box 24, Folder 456)
        - Appendix I: blues photocopy, with printer's annotations ("Shenstone's Billets") (Box 24, Folder 457)
        - Appendix II: typescript, corrected (The Tobacco-stopper Plot) (Box 24, Folder 458)
        - Appendix III: typescript, corrected (Box 24, Folder 459)
        - Appendix III: typescript, photocopy, with printer's annotations (Box 24, Folder 460)
        - Appendix IV: typescript, corrected (Dodsley's Fables) (Box 24, Folder 461)
        - Appendix IV: typescript, photocopy, with printer's annotations (Dodsley's Fables) (Box 24, Folder 462)
        - Appendix V: holograph (Shenstone's "Pastoral Ballad") (Box 24, Folder 463)
        - Appendix V: typescript, corrected (Shenstone's "Pastoral Ballad") (Box 24, Folder 464)
        - Appendix V: typescript, photocopy, with printer's annotations (Shenstone's "Pastoral Ballad") (Box 24, Folder 465)
        - Appendix V: typescript carbon (Shenstone's "Pastoral Ballad") (Box 24, Folder 466)
        - Appendix V: typescript, with printer's annotations (Shenstone's "Pastoral Ballad") (Box 24, Folder 467)
        - Appendix VI: typescript, photocopy, with printer's annotations, parts I-II (Box 24, Folder 468-69)
        - First galley proofs, with printer's annotations, copies A-C, 1976 Jun 14 (Box 25, Folder 470-72)
        - Paste-ups, parts I-V, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 473-77)
        - First page proofs, corrected, 1976 Sep 4 (Box 26, Folder 478-81)
        - First page proofs, corrected, 1976 Nov 30 (Box 26, Folder 482-84)
        - Second page proofs, corrected, 1977 Mar 7 (Box 26, Folder 485-88)
        - Dennis, Leah, "Introduction": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 489)
    - Project-related Materials
      - Correspondence
        - "A" general, 1978-79 (Box 26, Folder 490)
        - "B" general, 1967-71 (Box 26, Folder 491)
        - Baker, Stewart, 1964-74 (Box 26, Folder 492)
        - "C" general, 1940 (Box 26, Folder 493)
        - "D" general, 1961-76 (Box 26, Folder 494)
        - "E" general, 1968-84 (Box 26, Folder 495)
        - "F" general, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 496)
        - Falconer, A. F., 1954-84, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 497-98)
        - "G" general, 1951-69 (Box 27, Folder 499)
        - "H" general, 1954-68 (Box 27, Folder 500)
        - Houghton Library, Harvard University, 1958-60 (Box 27, Folder 501)
        - "I" general, 1962 (Box 27, Folder 502)
        - "K" general, 1968-69 (Box 27, Folder 503)
        - "L" general, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 504)
        - "M" general, 1940-69 (Box 27, Folder 505)
        - "O" general, 1937-68 (Box 27, Folder 506)
        - "P" general, 1964-68 (Box 27, Folder 507)
        - Pottle, Frederick A. [also contains biographical sketch of Thomas Percy], 1942-74, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 508)
        - Reddick, Allen, 1985-86 (Box 27, Folder 509)
        - Robinson, M. G., 1947-50 (Box 27, Folder 510)
        - "S" general, 1966-75 (Box 27, Folder 511)
        - Smith, David Nichol, 1958-62 (Box 27, Folder 512)
        - Thorpe, James, 1967-68 (Box 27, Folder 513)
        - Tillotson, Arthur, 1939 (Box 27, Folder 514)
        - "W" general, 1961-68 (Box 27, Folder 515)
        - Wood, Harriet, 1982-84 (Box 27, Folder 516)
        - "Y" general, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 517)
        - Yale University Library, 1960, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 518)
      - Manuscripts related to Percy consulted, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 519)
      - Percy editorial project: outline of file folder material as kept by Cleanth Brooks, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 520)
      - Smith, David Nichol: research material and notes, 1932-50, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 521-23)
      - Style sheet, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 524)
      - Useful notes on editing of the Percy correspondence, 1959-78, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 525)
      - Miscellaneous, 1963-64, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 526)
  - BOOKS
    The Books subseries is arranged alphabetically by title and thereunder according to the creative process.
    - American Literature: The Makers and the Making
      - Notes, miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 527-28)
      - Notes for salesmen of American Literature: draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 529)
      - Draft fragments: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 530-31)
      - Contents: notes, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 532)
      - Preface: draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 533)
      - Introduction: typescript carbon, corrected [draft A], 1967 Mar 25 (Box 28, Folder 534)
      - Introduction: typescript, corrected [draft B], 1968 Dec (Box 28, Folder 535)
      - Front matter: notes, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 536)
      - Preliminary note (1743-1826)
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 537)
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, photocopy, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 538)
        - Draft, typescript, photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 539)
      - Jefferson section: drafts, typescript, corrected
        - Early, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 540)
        - Later, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 541)
      - Early nineteenth-century American poetry: drafts, typescript, corrected, early (Box 28, Folder 542)
      - Bryant section
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 543)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 544)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 545)
      - Bryant headnotes: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 546)
      - Preliminary note (1826-1861): draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 547)
      - Poe, Thoreau, Holmes, et al.: drafts, typescript, corrected, early, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 548)
      - Poe notes, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 549)
      - Poe section
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 550)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 551)
        - Draft D, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 552)
        - Draft E, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 553)
      - Poe headnotes: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 554)
      - Thoreau notes, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 555)
      - Thoreau section
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 556)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 557)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 558)
        - Draft D, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 559)
      - Thoreau poems: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 560)
      - Stowe section: drafts, typescript, corrected (Box 29, Folder 561)
      - Preliminary note (1865-1914): draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 562)
      - Southern Section
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 563)
        - Research notes and drafts (Box 29, Folder 564-66)
      - Preliminary note (1914-1970)
        - "Live" research notes, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 567-68)
        - Early draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 569)
        - Later draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 570)
      - Moore section: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 571)
      - Faulkner section: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 572)
      - "Dead" notes, vols. I-II, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 573-74)
      - Brooks, Cleanth, Contributions of, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 575-76)
      - Lewis, R. W. B., Contributions of, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 577)
      - Warren, Robert Penn, Contributions of, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 578-80)
      - Brooks's notes for Warren and Lewis (Box 30, Folder 581)
      - Interview
        - Notes for Brooks-Warren Interview, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 582)
        - Transcription of interview between Brooks and Warren, typescript, corrected, first draft, tapes I-VII, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 583-85)
        - Transcription of interview between Brooks and Warren, typescript, corrected, second draft, tapes I-II, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 586)
        - Transcription of interview between Brooks and Warren, typescript, corrected, second draft, tapes III- VII (Box 31, Folder 587-88)
          See also: Box 96, folders 1997-2002
      - Things to do, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 589)
      - Galley proofs, corrected [incomplete], n.d. (Box 31, Folder 590)
      - American Literature: The Makers and the Making [booklet]
        - Booklet draft material, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 591)
        - Booklet, ca. 1973 (Box 31, Folder 592)
      - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 593)
      - Correspondence with editors, 1963-73, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 594-99)
    - An Anthology of Stories from the Southern Review
      - Introduction, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 31, Folder 600)
      - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 601)
      - Book reviews, 1953-54 (Box 31, Folder 602)
    - An Approach to Literature